Finding Aid for the Ogden Family Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Ogden Family Papers
undated
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0690
93.75 linear feet
- Files, Clippings (Box 1)
- Files (Box 2)
- Correspondence (Box 3)
- Files, clippings, letters (Box 4)
- Files (Box 6)
- Files, clippings, letters (Box 7)
- Files, clippings, magazine (Box 8)
- Pamphlets, magazine articles (Box 9)
- Magazines, Life, Presbyterian Life (Box 10)
- Clippings, letters (Box 11)
- Newspaper clippings (Box 12)
- Scrapbooks (2), clippings/Civil Rights and Family (Box 15)
- Oral history tapes - 1976 interview of Rev. Dunbar H. Odgen, Jr. with son Dunbar and wife Dorothy regarding Little Rock 1957-1958. 11 unidentified reel-to-reel tapes in box labeled: Hilversum IFTR ’86. (Box 18)
- Miscellaneous family (Box 20)
- Personal — clippings, photographs, letters, miscellaneous (Box 21)
- Yearbooks, 3/Davidson College — 7 autograph books (Box 22)
- Photograph Album, papers, letters (Box 24)
- Scrapbooks (Box 25)
- Correspondence, photographs, clippings (Box 28)
- Binders, reel to reel tapes (1950s-1960s), photographs (Box 29)
- Miscellaneous (Box 30)
- Movie reels (Box 33)
- 3-volume transcription and notes of 1976 interview of Rev. Dunbar H. Odgen, Jr. with son Dunbar and wife Dorothy regarding Little Rock 1957-1958. Small stack of stapled post-it notes with handwritten notes (Box 34)
  - Audio cassettes:
    Rufus King Young 8-23-2001 re: Little Rock
    Walter Clancy/Jean Gordon 8-27-2001
    Elizabeth Eckford 8-25-2001 re: Little Rock
- Slides — 7 flat Hollinger boxes (Box 35)
- Photographs and slides (Box 39)
- Miscellaneous, photographs, cards (Box 40)
- Photographs (Box 44)
- Slides (6 slide boxes) (Box 45)
- Photographs, letters, cards, clippings (Box 47)
- Photograph Albums (9) (Box 49)
- Photograph Albums (7) (Box 50)
- Photograph Albums (7) (Box 51)
- Photographs, postcards (Box 52)
- Slides (30 boxes x 36 slides) (Box 53)
- Slides (32 boxes) (Box 55)
- Slides 30 sets of 36 — Ogden Family, 1960 (Box 56)
- Slides 30 sets of 36 slides (Box 57)
- Ephemera File on 1997 Little Rock Anniversary (newspaper clippings, chapter drafts for 1997 interview with Elizabeth Eckford)) (Box 61)
- Correspondence/Cassettes 2 letters 1994 from Dorothy Ogden to Dunbar Ogden 1 letter 1994 from Jonathan Ogden to Dorothy Ogden “Early Memories of Christmas” by Dorothy C. Ogden Audio cassettes (8): Interview with Dorothy Ogden on, October 23, 1994 (Box 62)
- Books (Box 63)
- (Little Rock) Arkansas State Press microfilm: Aug 15, 1952 — Oct 30, 1959 (Bronx, NY) Open Door microfilm: Oct — Dec 1959 Drafts of description of Little Rock Nine at Central High School Newspaper clippings Oversized volume of historic Arkansas newspaper pages (Box 64)
- Photographs (Box 65)
- Photographs (Box 69)
- Letters, obituary, guest book (Box 70)
- 3-volume transcription and notes of 1976 interview of Rev. Dunbar H. Odgen, Jr. with son Dunbar and wife Dorothy regarding Little Rock 1957-1958. Second copy of set in Box 34 with lots of post-it notes marking corrections and notes to interview. (Box 71)
- Photographs, clippings (Box 72)
- Correspondence (Box 74)
- Correspondence (Box 75)
- Files, Theatre (Box 76)
- Files, Appointment Books (Box 77)
- Photographs, slides, appointment books (Box 78)
- Theater Research (Box 79)
- Sermons (Box 80)
- Photographs, slides, miscellaneous (Box 81)
- Miscellaneous Includes photocopy of “Walking My Lonesome,” an autobiography of Rev. Colbert Scott Cartwright — original is owned by Disciples of Christ Historical Society (Box 82)